<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chapliboy and the astra fellowship</title>
    <link>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on chapliboy and the astra fellowship</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 09:50:53 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>cellular</title>
      <link>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/cellular/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 09:50:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/cellular/</guid>
      <description>I had been harboring this idea of a game where you control the rules of a cellular automata, and use that to do spells and make things happen. It was an idea that had been in my head ever since the jams had started, and in the final jam, I decided that I would finally take up that challenge.
development Like all other jams, the technical part is the easy part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>deckbowler</title>
      <link>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/deckbowler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 09:50:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/deckbowler/</guid>
      <description>I really like the concept of deckbuilders. I think there is something really satisfying with a game where you have to adapt your playstyle on the fly, as you get different abilities, and then figure out how they all work together.
I thought it might be interesting to have a bowling game based around the same concept. Where you can have different goals every frame, and adapt your bowling strategy as you collect more abilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Juggler Prototype</title>
      <link>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/juggler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 11:52:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/juggler/</guid>
      <description>I got into juggling sometime during the pandemic. Its really simple. You just throw up a ball and catch it. The hard part is doing that three at a time. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently gotten back into it, and now I see it is really something that can be easily broken down into a system.
So I wanted to make a game about juggling. The &amp;ldquo;premise&amp;rdquo; is that you have control over some kind of robot, and you have to give it precise instructions, and it will learn to juggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensors n Signals</title>
      <link>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/sensors_n_signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 18:52:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/sensors_n_signals/</guid>
      <description>The theme for the second jam was Make it Thinky. We were encouraged to select any genre that we liked, and try to make a thinky experience out of it.
ThinkyGames.com defines thinky as
 Thinky games are those that ask you to carefully reason your way through puzzles and challenges; games brimming with curiosity and discovery. If you find yourself thinking through a problem and then, when the insights finally dawn on you, exclaiming “aha!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hiveminder</title>
      <link>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/hiveminder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 17:21:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fellowship.chapliboy.com/jams/hiveminder/</guid>
      <description>The goal for the first jam was to figure out how I can distill what I enjoy most about city builders, and build the simplest version of that for the jam. When I say city builder, I am mostly referring to games like Pharaoh and Caesar 3.
What I like the most about the genre-
 Growth. Starting off with a small colony and then slowly watching it grow over time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>